smartdraw.com 2016-04-06

# Privacy Policy Statement - About SmartDraw - SmartDraw Official Site

_Last updated: October 2nd, 2012_

SmartDraw respects and protects your privacy. This Privacy Policy describes how SmartDraw collects, uses, and shares information gathered from our users.

#### Your Choices

If you would like to express any concern you have about our use of your data, simply contact us by email at [privacy@smartdraw.com](mailto:privacy@smartdraw.com) or by phone at 1-800-768-3729.

If you no longer want to receive our marketing or product update mailings, you can remove your e-mail address from our mailing list by clicking on the automatic "unsubscribe" link in any of our mailings or by simply e-mailing us at [support@smartdraw.com](mailto:support@smartdraw.com?Subject=Unsubscribe).

At any time, you may also elect to withdraw your consent to us using your personal information for purposes other than the main functionality of the SmartDraw website (including the SmartShare service) by contacting support@smartdraw.com. If you request that we delete your personal information, we will cancel your SmartShare account and will no longer be able to provide the SmartShare services to you.

#### Collecting Personal Information

In order to provide you with access to SmartDraw's products and services, we require that you provide certain personal information. This information includes your name, mailing address, telephone number, email address, and password.

If you choose to purchase products or services through the SmartDraw website, we will also need your credit card number and expiration date if you want to use a credit card for payment purposes.

Personal information that SmartDraw collects also includes any personal files that you decide to submit or upload to the SmartShare service, any comments or progress updates that you post through the SmartShare service, and your activity viewing other users' documents and comments. Personal information collected by SmartDraw is transported through the internet by an encrypted connection and your personal files are stored encrypted upon receipt by SmartDraw. Your personal information will not be shared with third parties, unless it is made "public" by you while using the SmartShare service.

From time-to-time we collect information via surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary. You may choose whether or not to participate and thereby disclose any information about you. Information requested may include contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such education level, and job function). Contact information collected in this manner will be used only to notify the winners and award prizes. Survey information will be used only for purposes of improving the use and customer satisfaction of this site.

We do not knowingly collect information on children under the age of 18.

#### Cookies

To help improve your experience, we use "cookies" on our web site.

A cookie is simply a piece of data (e.g. an arbitrary number) that our server sends to your browser. Your browser may then store the cookie on your computer and read it back to our server if you visit our site again. These cookies allow us to create a more personalized experience for you while visiting our web site.

If you're concerned about cookies, you can have your browser notify you when it receives a cookie, giving you the choice to accept or decline it. Without cookies, however, you cannot log into your SmartDraw account and cannot use the SmartShare service.

#### How We Use Personal Information

Personal information we collect through the SmartDraw website may be used by us to (a) authenticate your identity when you register and each time you sign in; (b) notify you when subscriptions are due to expire and to pre-populate forms; and (c) otherwise as required by law.

Personal information we collect through the SmartDraw website - for example, your name, mailing address, and email address - may also be used by us to contact you regarding products and services and upcoming events we believe you might find of interest.

If you no longer want to receive our marketing or product update mailings, you can remove your e-mail address from our mailing list by clicking on the automatic "unsubscribe" link in any of our mailings or by simply e-mailing us at support@smartdraw.com.

SmartShare gives you the option to share files that you upload to the SmartShare service, any comments or progress updates that you post through the SmartShare service, your activity viewing other users' documents and comments, and your user profile, which may include your email address, physical address, biography, phone number and social media links. You may share these files privately with others that you specifically select, or make them public and post them on social media sites. The choice to keep files private, or to share files with others, or to make them public is entirely yours.

We also may use the personal information you provide for internal purposes, such as administration and operation of the SmartDraw website and SmartShare service, data analytics, and compliance with our legal obligations, policies and procedures.

#### Sharing Personal Information

We will not sell or rent your personal information, including your email address, to any third party under any circumstances. We will not share or otherwise disclose personal information about you, except as described here, where required by law, or with your express prior consent.

Personal information may also be transferred in connection with a business transition such as a merger, acquisition, restructuring, spin-off or other divestiture, insolvency, or asset sale involving SmartDraw and its company affiliates.

#### Protecting Personal Information

If you choose to purchase our products and/or services, your credit card number will be encrypted (scrambled) with state-of-the-art technology so that no one else can read it. Your credit card information will be stored, encrypted, for up to 4 days while the transaction is posted by our payment processor. You can verify this by looking for a closed lock icon in your web browser, or looking for "https" at the beginning of the address of the web page.

We maintain administrative, technical and physical safeguards to protect against loss, misuse or unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction of personal information you provide to SmartDraw. We control employee and contractor access to encrypted materials. We also employ secure transmission protocols in sending you emails and other electronic communications.

#### Visiting Other Websites

SmartDraw may provide links to relevant third-party sites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the content or privacy practices of these sites. We encourage you to be pro-active and read the privacy policies of any other sites that collect personal information. If you access another website from a link on the SmartDraw website, information collected while on the third party website will be subject to that website's privacy policy.

#### Updates to Privacy Policy

We will occasionally update this privacy policy to reflect changes in our services and customer feedback. When we post changes to this policy, we will revise the "last updated" date at the top of this policy. If there are material changes to this policy or in how SmartDraw will use your personal information, we will notify you either by prominently posting a notice of such changes prior to implementing the change or by directly sending you a notification. We encourage you to periodically review this statement to be informed of how SmartDraw is protecting your information.

#### Dispute Resolution

If you have questions, comments or complaints regarding this privacy policy or our privacy practices, please contact us at [privacy@smartdraw.com](mailto:privacy@smartdraw.com?Subject=SmartDraw%27s%20Privacy%20Policy).

#### Physical Address

SmartDraw Software, LLC  
9909 Mira Mesa Blvd. Suite 300  
San Diego, CA 92131  
Phone: 800-768-3729 (toll-free)  
Phone: 858-225-3300
